Victor Klynets

Front-end Developer

Kiev, Yangel Street, 16/2 +380509721609 | vityok3458@gmail.com

in ua.linkedin.com/in/victor-klynets

About me

I'm **Junior++ Front End Developer** with a decent experience in *building sites, Single Page Applications* and finding new, more flexible, highly efficient, more synthetic as well as more performing and elegant ways to build it.

A far-sighted *problem preventer*. Being highly *adaptable*, I'm able to quickly pick up and *work with any architecture or libraries* required. I can estimate the time needed to complete a task (and a project), plan and lead the work of a team of 3-5 people to complete a project respecting the deadlines.

Passionate about creating a favorable work environment through effective coordination and communication with managers, designers, developers and clients to produce stand-out work. Good analytical thinking with talent for identifying, scrutinizing and improving work processes

Employment

Front-end developer

February 2016 - October 2016

Mixera

As a Lead Front-end Developer my responsibilities were:

- Making a Single Page Application with ExtJS and React/Redux
- Creating custom solutions and working with a large project
- Analyzing performance and developing better solutions
- Working in team and managing tasks
- Mentoring new team members

Used technology stack:

- React/Redux
- ExtJS
- JavaScript ES5 / ES6, jQuery
- Grunt, Gulp, Webpack
- Git, npm
- REST API, WebSockets, GraphQL

Freelance Web Developer

November 2015 - January 2016

Independant Freelancer

- Quickly identified issues with existing web-sites
- Contacted clients to obtain more information and discuss design options
- Determine appropriate architecture, and other technical solutions, and make relevant reccomendations to clients

Education

Bachelor's Degree

NTUU Kyiv Polytechnic Institute

Studying software engineering at the third grade.

2014 - Present

Soft Skills

- English(upper-intermediate), Hungarian(native speaker), Ukrainian(native speaker), Russian(native speaker)
- Problem solver with a can do attitude
- Good understanding of industrial and organization psychology principles
- High level of communication
- Highly self- motivated and directed
- Good analytical thinking with talent for identifying, scrutinizing and improving work processes
- Equally comfortable working as a member of a team and independently

Hard Skills

Frontend Development

Building sites and Single Page
Applications.

JavaScript

Great knowledge of Vannila JS (ES5 and ES6).

JavaScript Frameworks and Libraries

ExtJS, React with Redux, Vue.js, jQuery, D3.js, Jasmine, shallow knowledge of Angular

Build systems and module bundlers

Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Bower

Other Technologies

- NodeJS
- Git, npm
- REST API, WebSockets, GraphQL

